Guide to the Sarah P. Duke Gardens records, 1926-2012 UA.10.08.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sarah P. Duke Gardens records
1926-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sarah P. Duke Gardens
UA.10.08.0001
24.5 Linear Feet
The Gardens were a gift from Mary Duke Biddle in honor of her mother, Sarah P. Duke (Mrs. Benjamin N.). Construction began in 1932 and the site was open to the public in 1934. Ellen Shipman (1869-1950) designed the plans for both the construction and the plantings for the new gardens. Collection contains materials pertaining to the origins and activities of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens including planting plans, calendars, correspondence, feasibility studies, annual reports, a card catalog of plantings, and publicity. Materials in the collection date from 1926-2012.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Sarah P. Duke Gardens records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1974, 1997, 1999, 2013.
Biographical/Historical note
taken from the Sarah P. Duke Garden website http://www.hr.duke.edu/dukegardens/history.htm
Much of the Gardens is located in a valley that the planners of Duke University in the early 1920s hoped to turn into a lake, but funds were short. For once, that problem was a blessing! Consequently, the idea of a lake with elegant fountains was abandoned and the first plants at this site were made in the early 1930s, a result of the vision and enthusiasm of Dr. Frederic M. Hanes, an early member of the original faculty of the Duke Medical School.
Dr. Hanes possessed a special love for gardening and was determined to convert the debris-filled ravine, by which he walked daily, into a garden of his favorite flower, the iris. He persuaded his friend, Sarah P. Duke, widow of one of the University's founders, Benjamin N. Duke, to give $20,000 to finance a garden that would bear her name.
In 1935, more than 100 flower beds (in the area which would become today's South Lawn) were in glorious bloom with 40,000 irises, 25,000 daffodils, 10,000 small bulbs, and assorted annuals, all of which were washed away in heavy summer rains and the flooding stream. By the time of Sarah P. Duke's death in 1936, the original gardens were destroyed. Dr. Hanes convinced her daughter, Mary Duke Biddle, to construct a new garden on higher ground, as a fitting memorial to her mother. Ellen Shipman (1869-1950), a pioneer in American landscape design, was selected to the plans for both the construction and the plantings for the new gardens.
Duke Gardens is considered Shipman's greatest work and a national architectural treasure, most of the some 650 other gardens she designed having long since disappeared.
The Sarah P. Duke Gardens today consists of four major parts: the original Terraces and their immediate surroundings, the H.L. Blomquist Garden of Native Plants (a representation of the flora of the southeastern United States), and the Culberson Asiatic Arboretum (devoted to plants of eastern Asia). There are five miles of allées, walks, and pathways throughout the Doris Duke Center and surrounding gardens.
Administratively, the Gardens are currently (2000) part of Facilities Management.
Scope and Contents note
General files contains materials pertaining to the origins and activities of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens including planting plans, calendars, correspondence, feasibility studies, annual reports, a planting card catalog, and publicity. Also in the collection is a VHS videocassette from 1996 "A Capital Campaign for the Center for the Duke Gardens," featuring Ted Koppel, and a DVD from 2004, "Crown Jewel of Duke University." The William Louis Culberson papers series contains administrative records pertaining to his directorship of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens from 1978-1998. Culberson was also Hugo L. Blomquist Professor of Botany and Chairman of the Department of Botany at Duke University. Also included are the records of Richard Fillmore, Assistant Director of the Gardens and "Horticulturalist in Charge." A further series of Garden Director Larry T. Daniels' papers is also part of the collection. These materials range in date from 1926-2012 and include correspondence, reports, donor material, personnel files, newspaper and magazine clippings, plans and drawings, and material relating to the creation of the Doris Duke Center.
Separated Material
Newsletters Flora and The Dirt have been separated from the collection, and are listed as periodicals. Flora, a newsletter for the Friends of the Gardens, has been published since 1979. The Dirt, the volunteers' newsletter, has been published since 1992.
Accession A2001-93, a commemorative object representing the Doris Duke Center has been separated and is housed as an artifact.
Accessions A97-3, A2000-54, A2000-68 are oversized technical drawings and are stored in oversize storage. Accession 2013-0034 included oversized technical drawings stored with the Daniel and Fillmore papers. These were seperated and are stored in oversize.
In June 2007 items including event brochures and flyers, history of Duke Gardens, maps, magazine articles, and newspaper clippings were removed from the record collection and placed into the Sarah P. Duke Gardens Reference collection.
Related Material
Sarah P. Duke Gardens Reference Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Kramer (Paul J.) Papers, 1856-1994 (bulk 1927-1974).
University Archives, Duke University.
Frederic Moir Hanes papers, 1927-1968.
Medical Center Library Archives, Duke University.
University Archives Photograph Collection, 1861-2006.
University Archives, Duke University.
Banner
Gardens Drawings and Designs, Series 5, is currently being re-processed, so this guide may be inaccurate. Items are not available for immediate access in the reading room and must be requested at least seven days in advance.
Shipman, Ellen; Culberson, William Louis; Albrecht, Edmund -- Photographer; Fillmore, Richard H.; Sarah P. Duke Gardens -- handbooks, manuals, etc.; Daniel, Larry T.; Durden, Robert Franklin; Sarah P. Duke Gardens; Sarah P. Duke Gardens; Sarah P. Duke Gardens -- History; Sarah P. Duke Gardens -- photographs
- General Files, 1934-2002, bulk 1958-1999, 3 boxes
  - Anderson Street Parking Lot - Modifications, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 2001-2002 c.1 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 2001-2002 c.2 (Box 1)
  - Asiatic Arboretum Pool Gazing Arbor, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Asiatic Arboretum Pool Gazing Arbor Paving Plan, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Blomquist Gate (Box 1)
  - Calendar, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Calendar, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - "A Capital Campaign for the Center for the Duke Gardens," with Ted Koppel, 1996 --VHS videocassette - [A99-1] (Box 1)
  - "Center for the Duke Gardens," Feasibility Study for the, Sept. 1995 (Box 1)
  - Checklists of Plants, 1984- (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1994 (Box 1)
  - Daylilly Planting Plan, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Duke Gardens Through the Years/ Robert T. Durden, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Explanatory Notes in the I-40 extension location and storm draining study, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Garden Water Course Report, Moriece and Gary Landscape Architects, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Gohdes Scuppernong Grape Arbor, 1999 (A2000-67) (Box 1)
  - Lily Pool Planting Plan, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Moriece and Gary - Status of Plant Materials Along the Watercourse Nursery Frame and Bed Plan, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Plans, 1964- (Box 1)
  - Report of Sarah P. Duke Memorial Garden, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Running Inventory and Planting Plan, 1958-1967 (9 folders) (Box 2)
  - Spray Pond Report by William S. Leong Incl. watercolor drawings, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Stationery -- note cards [1999] (Box 2)
  - Terrace Planting Plan, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Utility and Water Distribution, Report, Moriece and Gary, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Doris Duke Center (Box 3)
  - Planting Plan for Proposed Water Garden, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Peony Planting Plan, 1985 (Box 3)
- William Louis Culberson papers, 1960-2002, bulk 1990-1999, 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The William Louis Culberson papers series contains administrative records pertaining to his directorship of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens from 1978-1998, and ranges in date from 1960-2002. A majority of the material ranges in date from 1990-99. This material is also restricted for twenty-five years from date of origin. Material present includes correspondence, reports, donor material, personnel files, newspaper and magazine clippings, plans and drawings, and material relating to the creation of the Doris Duke Center. Also present is a collection of correspondence from 1989 (foldered seperately) between Culberson and then University President, H. Keith H. Brodie, concerning the location of a proposed Art Museum on campus.
  - Alexander, Irving, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
  - Anatomical Gifts, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, L.E., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, Taimi, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Angell, Joan L., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Angier, Jonathan, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Asiatic Arboretum, 1991, undated (Box 4)
  - Atkin, Tony, 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Baker, Cynthia, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Baver, Scott, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Molly Bernheim Memorial, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Billings, W.D., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Bishop, Sandra, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Blomquist, undated (Box 4)
  - Board of Advisors, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Bonsberg, Sarah S., 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Bunting, Kay, 1997-1998, undated (Box 4)
  - Burness, John F., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Brodie, Brenda, 1996-1996 (Box 4)
  - Byrd, Warren, 1994-1998, undated (Box 4)
  - Campus Club, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Carr, Jean, 1989-1998 (Box 4)
  - Center, architectural history, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Center, campaign, 1996, undated (Box 4)
  - Cole, Charity, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Coppridge, A.J., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Crovitz, Herbert F., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Daniel, Larry T., 1992-1999 (Box 4)
  - Curtin, Helen, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
  - Dark, Teresa P., 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Burke, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Dawson, Mary H., 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Directorship, 1991-1998 (Box 4)
  - Dodson, Andrew, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Doell&Doell, ASLA, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Drill, Elizabeth Craven, 1990-1998 (Box 4)
  - Doris, Duke, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Duke Endowment, 1996-1997, undated (Box 4)
  - Durden, Robert F., 1990-2001 (Box 4)
  - Durham Merchants Association, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Eddleman, Edith, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Education Program, 1994, undated (Box 4)
  - Elkins, Mary Alice, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Eshelman, P., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Feasbility Study, 1994, undated (Box 4)
  - Finances, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Fowler, Ruth, 1994-1997 (Box 4)
  - Frye, Lin, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Freeman, Pamela, 1995-1996, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Fuqua, Dorothy, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Gebel, Emile L., 1994 (Box 4)
  - Gehman, Scott, 1996, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Gift Records, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Gohdes-Batin, B., 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Goodwin, Nancy, 1993-1997, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Gray, Tom, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Grigg, Mrs., 1996, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Hammett, Karen M., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Hamrick, Harvey, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Hammrick, Ladd, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Hanes, Eldridge C., 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Hanes, F.M., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Harmel, Merel H., 1989-1990, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Harriet J. Phelps Charitable Trust, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Hartlage, Richard, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Hayter, Reynolds, & Jewel Proposal, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Hemric, Chuck, 1994-1995, undated (Box 4)
  - History, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Horticulture Magazine, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Horton, Alice, book graphics, 1992, 1994-1999 (Box 4)
  - Intern Program, 1993, undated (Box 4)
  - Jackson, Kathleen, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Jenkins, Harry, 1995, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Jewell, Linda, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Carol, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Paul, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Kanzaki, Hisae, 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - Kellogg, Sally Ann, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Kennan, Thomas S., 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - Keohane, Nan O., 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Kerckoff, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Kirby Foundation, 1994-1997 (Box 4)
  - Koppel, Ted, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Koslofsky, Regis, 1994-1997 (Box 4)
  - Kramer, Paul, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Kurtz, Carol, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Labels for Plants and Books, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Ladd, Laura, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Landscape In-House, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Land-Use Study, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Le Duc, Alice, undated (Box 4)
  - Langford, T.A., 1994-1998 (Box 4)
  - Leong, W.B.S., undated (Box 4)
  - Leubuscher, F.H., 1988 (Box 4)
  - Lewis Street, 1992, 1998, undated (Box 4)
  - Lindsay, R., 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Livingstone, B., 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Maziarz, D.M., 1998 (Box 4)
  - McAdoo, Jane, 1998 (Box 4)
  - McCracken, Sarah, 1996 (Box 4)
  - McEachren, John, 1990 (Box 4)
  - McIntyre, F.H., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Memorial Garden, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Mertens, Joan R., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Meyer, Horst, 1994-1998 (Box 4)
  - Miller, Lynden, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Mission, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Nakayama, Yukio, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Nashold, A., 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Newborg, Barbara, 1997 (Box 4)
  - O'Brien, Carol, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Oliver, Thomas K., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Owens, Mike, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Pearce, John, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - Perry-Camp, Jane, 1996, undated (Box 4)
  - Piva, John, 1994-1998 (Box 5)
  - Pless, Jack, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Powell, James, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Price, Mary, 1996, undated (Box 5)
  - Putman, C.E., 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Putman, Mary, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Panek, Mary, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Parking, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - Raulston, J.C., undated (Box 5)
  - Rausch, G.L., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Rawn, W., A.I.A., 1996, undated (Box 5)
  - Rees, Joe, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, S., 1991-1995, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Reid, Charles, 1996-2001 (Box 5)
  - Robert, James S., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Ralph P., 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Ross, Alan, 1998-1999, undated (Box 5)
  - Ross, David, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Runte, Douglas W., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Schiebel, Nan, 1995-1997, undated (Box 5)
  - Schlayer, Clotilde, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Semans, 1990-1998 (Box 5)
  - Semans, James, 1996, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Sharp, John D., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Sheehan, Cecil, undated (Box 5)
  - Shelton Pond, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Shepard, Robert, 1995, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Shibata, Michiko, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Shipman, E., 1994-1998 (Box 5)
  - Shipman Historical Marker, 1993-1994, undated (Box 5)
  - Shipman Symposium, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Siemer, Richard, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Simes, Molly, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Mark, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Spengler, Dot, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Stanley Smith Horticultural Trust, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - Statuary, undated (Box 5)
  - Steffeck, Ed, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Stetler, Nevin, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Storage, Greer Street, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Strohbehn, Barbara, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Steinhardt, Michael, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Stern, Kay, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Strohbehn, John, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Sundial, 1988-1990, undated (Box 5)
  - Teabeaut III, J.R., 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Telephones, Emergency, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Terrace Shop, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
  - Terraces, 1991-1992, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Town and Country Garden Club, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Trask, Tallman, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - Trent Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Video, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Walker, Joseph E., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Warren Imports, 1986-1997 (Box 5)
  - Confidential, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Weintraub, E. Roy, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Whalen, Anna, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - White, Joe, 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - White, Richard, A., 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - White, Virginia, 1995-1996, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Wickersham, Faye, 1995, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Wilcox, Allen, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Wilkins, R.R., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Williams, L. Neil, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Willimon, William H., 1998 (Box 5)
  - Wister, John C., undated (Box 5)
  - Witzleben, Charles, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Wood, Carol, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Woodard, Sarah, 1996, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Zapolski, Todd, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Gardens of Peace, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Duke Garden Gift Index, 1981-1992 (Box 5)
  - Planting Lists, undated (Box 5)
  - Campus Planting, 1960-1964, 1974 (Box 5)
  - First Counsel, Inc., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Ross, Johnston, & Kersting, Inc., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center Material, Atkin, Olshin, & Lawson-Bell, A.A., 1999 (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center Material, Atkin, Olshin, & Lawson-Bell, A.A., 1998 (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center Material, Building and Grounds Committee, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center, 1998-1999, undated (Box 5)
  - Doris Duke Center, Landscape drawings, 1996, undated (Box 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 5)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Culberson and H. Keith H. Brodie concerning site of proposed Art Museum, 1989 (Box 5)
- Richard Fillmore papers, 1926-1985, 1 boxes
  - Anderson Gate Plans, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Acquisitions List, 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Archives 1, 1960-1963 (Box 6)
  - Archives 2, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
  - Barnes-Brown Entrance, 1961-1966 (Box 6)
  - Barnes, Lois; Screens, 1961-1972 (Box 6)
  - Barnes Studio, 1960-1963 (Box 6)
  - Barnes Studio, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Barnes Studio Gates, 1961 April-December (Box 6)
  - Barnes Studio Main Gates, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Barnes Studio Sculpture, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1945-1952 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1945-1956 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1956-1961 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Clippings, 1972 June (Box 6)
  - Crab Apples, 1937-1944 (Box 6)
  - Daniel, Larry Memos, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Fillmore to Kramer, 1976 June-November (Box 6)
  - Flower Gardening Clippings, 1926-1941 (Box 6)
  - Garden Boundaries, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
  - Gates, Screens, 1961-1972 (Box 6)
  - Gehman, 1996-1992 (Box 6)
  - General, 1952-1962 (Box 6)
  - General, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - Greenhouse and Service Building, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Hemerocallis, Old Records, Webb, 1934-1949 (Box 6)
  - Henrickson, 1960-1966 (Box 6)
  - Heustis, 1975 October 27 (Box 6)
  - Iris Old Orders, 1936-1943 (Box 6)
  - Kramer, Paul J., 1936-1974 (Box 6)
  - Laurel Lake Nursery, 1965-1974 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1957-1962 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1959-1964 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1961 May-July (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1962 May 27 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1962 March-October (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1966 July 4 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Leong, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Leong, Main Enterance, Main Gate, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
  - Leong, Memorial Area, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Leong, Memorial Mall, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Leong, Spray Pond, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Leong, Visit, 1962 January (Box 6)
  - Marliac, 1963 March (Box 6)
  - Burle Marx, 1964-1985 (Box 6)
  - Master Plan, 1975 April-May (Box 6)
  - Matzke, Ruther, Snyder, 1964 (Box 6)
  - McDaniel, 1959-1966 (Box 6)
  - McHutchinson, 1958 (Box 6)
  - McGuire, Landscape Architect, 1966-1973 (Box 6)
  - Memorandum, Wister Report, 1935-circa 1940 (Box 6)
  - Memorial Gates, 1936 August-November (Box 6)
  - Modern Gates, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Narcissus, old orders, 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Narcissus, Webb, 1939-1941 (Box 6)
  - National Arboretum, 1964-1976 (Box 6)
  - New York Times, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Nicolin, 1957 April (Box 6)
  - Nordine, 1957-1961 (Box 6)
  - Old Orders, 1934-1948 (Box 6)
  - Original Box Tree, 1937-1940 (Box 6)
  - Peonies, 1926-1944 (Box 6)
  - Photographs and Negatives, 1963 August 16 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, Shady Garden, 1960s (Box 6)
  - A Revision of Hexastylis of North America, 1957 January 9 (Box 6)
  - Roses, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Sarah P. Duke Gardens, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
  - Semans, 1960-1972 (Box 6)
  - Semans, 1967-1977 (Box 6)
  - Semans, Spray Pond Revision, 1963-1967 (Box 6)
  - Shrubs and Trees, old orders, 1934-1940 (Box 6)
  - Storm Drain Plans, 1975 October (Box 6)
  - Dr. Stout, Hemerocallis (Daylillies), 1946-1948 (Box 6)
  - Terrace, 1962-1971 (Box 6)
  - Terraces Construction, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Trip July 9-15 Mt. Kisco, NY, 1946 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Botanical Garden, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
  - Whitford, Dir. Ops. and Maintenance, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - Woodland Nurseries, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
- Larry T. Daniel papers, 1934-2012, 2 boxes
  - Development Projects, 1960-2001
    - Alexander Project, 1997-1999 (Box 7)
    - Anatomical Gifts, 1998-2000 (Box 7)
    - Anderson House, 1993-2000 (Box 7)
    - Angle Ampitheater, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Arboretum Gate, Shelter, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Arnot Bench, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
    - Azalea Court, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Azalea Court, McMillin, 1999 December 30 (Box 7)
    - Beischer Bench, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Benches, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Bench, Traffic Circle, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
    - Bereni Bridge, 1994-2001 (Box 7)
    - Bernheim/Vaughn Bridge, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
    - Besterman Bench, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
    - Blair/Blomquist Millstone, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Blomquist Garden, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Biersack, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Blazey Memorial, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
    - Blomquist Garden, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Blomquist Garden Shelter, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Blomquist Garden Wall, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Blomquist Secret Garden, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
    - Bolcock Wooden Bridge, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Borstelmann Bench, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Bunting/Rocks, 1996-1998 (Box 7)
    - Butterfly Garden, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Carrington Bench, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Clippinger Lantern, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
    - Crovitz, Blomquist Basin, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Construction, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Construction, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Curtin Urn, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Davis Bench, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Daylilly Garden Club, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
    - DeMaria Bench, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Demerit Bell Bench, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Despository Beuhler, 1990-1996 (Box 7)
    - Diamond Stone, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Dogwood Stone Azalea Court, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
    - Drinking Fountain, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
    - Drinking Fountain, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Driscoll Store Basin, 1993-1997 (Box 7)
    - Durden Memorial Bench in Terraces, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Eitokaji Lantern, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
    - Emile Saint- Amand, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Englewood Cut Stone, 1987-1998 (Box 7)
    - Erlenbach Bench, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Eshelman Bridge, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Fence, 1961-1967 (Box 7)
    - Fowler East Meets West, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Fowler Gate, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - Fowler Stone Pagoda, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - French Bench, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Front Gates, 1961-1985 (Box 7)
    - Garden Fountain Statues, 1977-1998 (Box 7)
    - Geissinger/Taitt Memorial, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Goldfish, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Grape Arbor, 1996-1999 (Box 7)
    - Grate Bench, 1981-1992 (Box 7)
    - Greenhouse, 1960-circa. 2000 (Box 7)
    - Greenhouse, New Location, 1959-1974 (Box 7)
    - Hamrick, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
    - Hanes Gate, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Harding Stone Work, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Holton Project, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Betty Jane Gould Horton, 1998 (Box 7)
    - James Powell Pond Landing, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Jane McAdoo/Betty Gilbert Barron, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Japanese Garden Lantern, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Japanese Iris Garden, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Jefferson Quotation, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Jennes Memorial, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Kim Specie Rose Collection, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Lanterns, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Laugford Bench, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Leubuscher, 1988-1992 (Box 7)
    - Limestone Morton & Co., 1985-1992 (Box 7)
    - Martens Project, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
    - Maziarz Pond, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - Memorial Gate Plaque, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
    - Memorial Project, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Mertens, 1998 (Box 7)